Well, Mom has 4 million. Well, where
Ну вот есть у мамы 4 млн Ну куда Мама
can Mom put these 4 million? I can’t understand. Well,
может деть эти 4 млн Я не могу понять Ну
most likely, they’ll pay off their loan for the
скорее всего ну выплатят кредит свой на
house and maybe they’ll help me because,
дом и возможно мне помогут потому что
as Mom tells me, I’m the only
как мне мама говорит я единственный
child in the family now. And they’ll help you with
сейчас ребёнок в семье А помогут тебе
something. Well, either  study maybe an apartment
чем Ну либо учёба может быть квартира
somehow else Well, that is, in principle
как-то ещё А ну то есть в принципе
it turns out Well, it is logical that if your brother is no longer there, then
получается Ну логично что уже брата нет
you can buy an apartment for 4 million
то квартиру можно купить тебе на 4 ляма
so it turns out Yes, I have this apartment It
так получается да у меня эта квартира
would be better if my brother were alive
Лучше бы чтобы у меня брат был живой Не
Well, if he is no longer there  all the same Yes all the
ну если его уже нет всё равно Да всё
same Well, yes, that's how it turns out Well,
равно Ну да вот так вот получается Ну
what to do now Maybe it sounds
что теперь делать Может быть звучит по
mercantile But what else Well, yes, you
меркантильной Но а что ещё-то Ну да от
can't give up the apartment Well, you
квартиры уже не откажешься Ну брата уже
can't get your brother back anyway Like if it's better
не вернёшь всё равно Типа если лучше
to have an apartment than neither an apartment nor a
иметь квартиру чем ни квартиры ни
brother  don't switch not a switch I
брата не переключайтесь не переключатель
communicate I want to communicate normally with Russians
общаюсь Я хочу нормально с русскими
you And you And what are you You are from America I I I
вы А ты А ты что ты Ты из Америки я я я
Can you be informal I allow I am from
Можно на ты я разрешаю я родом из
Rostov But I live in California now 18
Ростова Но живу сейчас в Калифорнии 18
years but Support I
лет но Поддержи
also want to live there how many years have you lived
тоже хочу там жить сколько лет ты живёшь
in California  I've been living in California for 18 years now,
в Калифорнии 18 лет уже живу в
please tell me what it's like to
Калифорнии через расскажите пожалуйста а
live there, pros and cons
как там жить вообще плюсы и минусы
now. Yes, you can show me. Where are you from?
сейчас Да можно показать Вы откуда сами
From Russia. Well, I understand. The city is Kirov. Kir
из России ну я и понял город Киров Кир
Vyatka. Yes, my mother is from Vyatka. My
Вятка Да да у меня мама из Вятки родом
heart is just great. It's awesome. Yes,
вам сердечко Просто классно это круто да
she is.  she arrived she arrived in ro in Rostov to
она приехала она приехала в ро в Ростов
study how is it there eh how Well it's cool It's warm It's
учиться как там э как Ну классно Тепло
warm yeah The only thing is that there
Тепло да Единственное что вот это пожары
were fires We saw fires Yes there were in
были видели пожары Да были в
California yes yes mine burned down The dacha is
Калифорнии да да вот у меня сгорела Дача
just there it's terrible It's
как раз там ужас Это
very And now And now where are you not
очень А сейчас А сейчас где тыц не у
I have a house and I have a
меня есть дом а есть
dacha I live in I live in Sacramento And this is
дача Я живу в Я живу в Сакраменто А это
near Los Angeles I had a dacha
возле лос-анджелеса у меня была дача как
just saw this area where Hollywood is
раз видели вот этот район где Голливуд
Yes, many Americans have dachas like that
Да там многих американцев дачи такие
Well, like a summer house to come
есть Ну типа летний домик чтобы приехать
to the coast Yes, and it turns out yes
на побережье Да и получается да там
everything burned down there, everything burned down Yes, who are you studying to be,
сгорело всё вот так всё сгорело Да вы на
what are we studying to be teachers,
кого учитесь что мы на учителей учимся
English teacher, I really want to go to
учитель английского очень хочется в
America And tell me the pros and cons,
Америку А расскажите плюсы и минусы
in general, how did you get there, in general, now,
вообще както приехали туда вообще сейчас
now I will tell you I have more than once,
сейчас я скажу Мне вот не раз учитель
English teacher, I  it's interesting because
английского Мне интересно потому что у
many of our
многих наших
citizens have British English have
э граждан есть British English есть
American English Yes, can you count
American English Да вот можешь посчитать
to 20 in English I want to hear either your
по-английски до 20 я хочу послушать или
pronunciation is English or American
произношение английское или американское
Can you count
у тебя Можешь считай
d 2 3 4 Si 7
д 2 3 4 Si 7
8 super Yes, in general, normal
8 супер Да вообще нормальное
pronunciation just like in  California at
произношение пря как в Калифорнии у на
Nor I like British pronunciation
Нор Мне нравится Британское произношение
I always wanted American Well
Я всегда хотела американское Ну
American Yes American yes Well listen you should
американское Да American да Ну слушай ты
just brush up here you could live here for
бы тут просто подтянула бы пожила тут
like six months I too at first when I
например полгода Я сначала тоже когда
arrived at first it was a shock for me Because
приехал сначала для меня был шок Потому
since we studied English in Russia
что так как мы учили английский в России
and so  how is it completely different here well
и так как тут это совсем по-другому ну
in half a year everything adapts and in general it
за полгода всё адаптируется И вообще
becomes good and how do you want to
стаёт хорошо а как вам вообще хотите
move to America Yes very much well
переехать в Америку Да очень сильно ну
after college why Well suddenly there will be an
после института почему Ну вдруг будет
opportunity Why is the
возможность Почему
program at least cool And why
программе хотя бы прикольно А зачем вот
well Work and Travel there maybe in  Russia
ну Work and Travel там может в России
can stay normally with us in
можно нормально остаться у нас туже в
California there are
Калифорнии там
all sorts of nete in this state there are many
всякие нете в этот штат есть же много
states in America how many states are there 50
штатов в Америке сколько штатов 50 с
something yes And why come to America
чем-то да А зачем приезжать в Америку
that's why I went Because  I Well, at least
вот я поехал Потому что я Ну хотя бы
just visit just visit
просто хотя бы побывать просто посетить
Well, travel to see the country
Ну попутешествовать посмотреть страну
why did you come yes I'll explain look I
зачем приехали да я объясню смотрите Я
teach anthropology here I studied to be
преподаю тут антропологию Я учился на
an anthropologist but this specialty is
антрополога но у нас эта специальность в
absolutely not in demand in Russia I was
России абсолютно не востребована Меня
invited to study for a master's degree
пригласили на магистратуру поучиться 2
in California for 2 years I stayed to study  for
года в Калифорнии я поучи остался на
postgraduate studies uh defended a dissertation And
аспирантуру ээ защитил диссертацию А
if you defend a dissertation you as a
если ты защищаешь диссертацию ты как
scientist can then get accelerated
учёный можешь тогда получить ускоренное
citizenship received citizenship stayed
гражданство получил гражданство остался
teaching at the university you are a very smart
преподаю в университете вы очень умный
person salary salary is true not
человек зарплата зарплата правда не
very big yes there 99,000 dollars a
очень большая да там 99.000 долларов в
month but in your opinion that is only 9000
месяц но это по вашему 9000 всего лишь
dollars for Russia  what money Well for
доллара для России какие деньги Ну для
Russia it is if my mother receives a
для России это если у меня мама получает
pension in Rostov 18,600 that is 186
в Ростове пенсию 18.600 то есть 186
dollars then And what by the way What do you
долларов то А чему кстати Как вы
think
считаете
why Why do you think it
почему Как вы считаете почему так
turns out that in our Russia there is oil
получается что в нашей России есть нефть
gas gold diamonds And everyone lives so
газ золото алмазы А все живут так
poorly Well in  anyway, and how
бедно Ну в любом случае а а сколько мы
[ __ ] old are we now? It turns out we are 43 years old and
бляд сейчас получается 43 года а
we moved at
переехали в
20. Subtract 18 and that will be how much  25 25 25
20 Отними 18 и будет сколько 25 25 25
that's right, well done And where did you study
правильно молодец это А где вы учились
before that I'm telling you in Rostov I studied at the
до этого я же говорю в Ростове учился в
Rostov State College,
Ростовском государственном в колледже
University, University, what kind of
университете университет какой
college, college, ours, Russian college
колледж колледж наши российский колледж
- This is some kind of crap for America
- Это для Америки это какая-то отстой
And where are you studying
вообще А вы где учитесь
now and we are here  in Kirov study VSU
сейчас а мы у себя в Кирове учи ВГУ
Vyatka State University
Вятский государственный университет
cool Yes interesting And who are you by
прикольно Да интересно А вы сами по
nationality Vyatichi
национальности кто вятичи
Buryati Well what do you mean Vyatichi Well
буряти Ну как в смысле вятичи Ну
Kirov Kirov
Кировский Кировская
region Well you are Vyatichi yes yes I understand yes that is there are
область Ну вы вятичи да да понял да то
Russians there are Vyatichi there are
есть есть Русские есть вятичи есть там
Buryats
буряти
understood And you are you yourself from  Kirov or
понял А вы это вы сами из Кирова или
somewhere in the woods Well, we have different ones here Well, I'm
где-то из лесов Ну у нас разные тут ну я
from Kotelnich I'm from Kirov directly and where are you
из котельнича Я из Кирова прямо а вы
from From Kotelnich it's somewhere there in the
откуда Из котельнича это где-то там в
woods Yeah, that's it Well, not directly in the woods a
лесах Да ну это Ну не прямо в лесах
village Well, in the region there 100 km from ki from
деревня Ну в области там 100 км от ки от
kiro Well there are already like bears walking around like that
киро Ну там уже типа медведи ходят такое
yeah yeah I have there for example on
да типа Ну да у меня там например на на
this there are foxes there for example on a chain
этом там лисы там например на цепи
bears  they sit mostly no no no at my place
медведи сидят в основном не не не у меня
Mom told me She's from Kirov from
Мама рассказывала Она же из Кирова из
Vyatka said that there in these uh in
Вятки говорила что там вот в этих ээ в
Kirov itself it's normal and there are a lot of
самом Кирове Норм а очень много
populated areas in the region What's there
населённых пунктов в области Да что там
Can a Bear come to the street like
Может Медведь прийти на на улицу вот
this from the forest Well he's everywhere  maybe in
такое из леса Ну он везде может в
principle I understood go Well if people
принципе понял перейти Ну если люди
live near the forest And where you are there
живут рядом с лесом А у вас там как
everything is calm, they don't bomb Well I saw and in
спокойно всё не бомбят Ну я видел а в
Kotelnich drones were flying And what is there in
Котельниче дроны летали А что там в
Kotelniki and there is the main Bridge
Котельниках такое а там главный Мост
which Well thanks to which
который Ну благодаря которому перевозят
all tanks are transported ammunition if this  the bridge
все танки боеприпасы если бы этот мост
was blown up the ammunition would not have started to
взорвали боеприпасы бы не стали бы
arrive I understand and Vato has friends
поступать понял а у вато знакомых есть
who have already died in the
кто погиб уже на
war I have a brother but I do
войне У меня брат родной да Но я ещё
n't know yet he hasn't been in touch for 4 months
пока что не знаю он 4 месяца на связь не
And how did he end up in the war under
выходил А как он попал на войну по
contract he broke up with his girlfriend  he
контракту он с девушкой расстался с
broke up with his girlfriend and
девушкой расстался и
went And when he went in
пошёл А когда он пошёл в
September twenty-four That is, he wanted to
сентябре дцать чет То есть он захотел
go kill people in Ukraine for money,
пошёл за деньги убивать людей в Украине
but not for money, he just
но не то чтобы за деньги просто он
broke up He was with a girl for 7 years, it
расстался Он был с девушкой 7 лет это
was his whole love  life they
была его любовь всей жизни они
broke up
расстались
and we ourselves did not know about it he just he
и мы сами об этом не зная он просто он
was sitting with me well that is visiting me
сидел у меня ну то есть в гостях у меня
like Yes and the next day my mother
как Да и на следующий день мне мама
calls me that Anton is my brother he left
звонит о том что Антон брат мой он ушёл
he signed a contract and on the same day
он Подписал контракт и в этот же день
as he  I signed the contract on the same day
как он Подписал контракт в этот же день
they sent it, he contacted us for another 2 weeks
его отправили он ещё 2-т недели с нами
and from about the end of
выходил на связь и примерно с конца
September, from 2nd somewhere around September, he didn’t
сентября с 2 там где-то сентября он не
contact us more than once, in September I
выходил на связь не раз он в сентябре
signed the contract and since the end of September he hasn’t
Подписал контракт и с конца сентября не
contacted us.  in touch
выходил Уже на связь
yes that is he didn't fight and it
да то есть он не повоевать и месяца
turns out a month No he
получается Нет он повоевать
didn't fight on September he didn't get in touch from the twenty-
сентября не выходил на связь с двадцать
seventh he fought
седьмого он повоевать
and didn't get in touch anymore And where did he
и больше не выходил на связь А где он
fight there Kherson Kursk And on m something
воевал там Херсон Курск А на м что-то
I have friends in Ukraine I  maybe
У меня есть знакомые в Украине Я может
I'll get in touch because they have
свяжусь потому что у них есть
their own people who work with prisoners, they're from the
эти свои на пленными они работают они из
Red Cross, so they can look for
Красного Креста вот могут поискать там
some city there that was captured in September and
какой-то в сентябре город захватывали и
I don't remember Honestly, what's the
я не помню Честно какой
name Sedelnikov with an e
на Как фамилия Седельников через е
now Yes, I'll
сейчас Да я
write it down I have a friend  from the
запишу Я у меня есть знакомый из
Red Cross maybe he is somewhere in captivity
Красного Креста может он где-то в плену
and they just won't let him call
и просто ну не дают позвонить
di
ди
Sidelnikov Anton Andreevich Anton
Сидельников Антон Андреевич Антон
Andreevich native of Vyatka
Андреевич уроженец Вятки
Yes Kiro Kiro he is from the Oparinsky district Well
Да киро киро он из опаринского района Ну
this is the Kirov
это Кировская
region and district what is his date of birth do you
область и район дата рождения какая у
remember
него помнишь
yes How many days in March
да В марте сколько
1995 he  20 years 29 He's 30 this
1995 ему 20 лет 29 Ему 30 лет в этом
year and ugh yeah I'm 30 yet Yes I wrote it all down
году а тьфу да 30 я ещ Да всё я записал
I'll send it to the guys they're from the Red Cross
я скину ребятам они из Красного Креста
They're just uh Well my friends uh they're
Они как раз ээ Ну знакомые мои ээ они
Belarusians themselves Belarusians they live in
сами белорусы белорусы оно живут в
Ukraine they work at the Red Cross They
Украине работают в красном кресте Они
communicate just  with these
общаются как раз с этими с
prisoners of war, uh, are they looking or are they
военнопленными ээ смотрят или у них там
doing well there Yes, perhaps yes, perhaps, that there
всё хорошо Да Возможно да возможно что
is such a thing, but do you remember what city is
есть такой да а не помнишь какой город
where it is Because from different directions
где его Потому что с разных направлений
to different ones they
в разные
can I don’t know I can look now
могут Я не знаю я могу сейчас посмотреть
Maybe he threw me a city by correspondence
Может быть он мне кидал по переписке
where to look it's interesting
город куда посмотри интересно
yes then it's clear there from different
да просто тогда понятно там с разных
directions to different places
направлений в разные свозят их э места
Yes here he didn't
Да тут он не
write Mariupol no no no  Mariupol already
написал Мариуполь не не не Мариуполь уже
It was a long time ago I
Это давно
don't even
было даже не
remember at A what are they saying to him where
помню при А что его эти говорят вте где
he signed And there is an incomprehensible situation
он подписва А там во непонятная ситуация
for 4 months nothing Nobody knows even at the
за 4 месяца ничего Никто не знает даже в
military registration and enlistment office no one at all no one
военкомате никто вообще никто такого
ever like that they turn out mot specially
никогда они получается мот специально
delay so as not to pay mom this
тянут чтобы не выплачивать маме это
compensation Well  I don't know but we have a
компенсацию Ну я не знаю но у нас
friend who hasn't contacted him for a month
знакома у них месяц на связь с не
but a month later it turned out that
выходил но спустя месяц оказалось то что
he had been lying in the morgue for a long time.
он в морге уже лежит давным-давно
They specially me but not four, the
Они специально ме но не четыре же
difference is big anyway for 4 months
разница большая всё равно на 4 месяца
it would have been possible to at least have some  -to give
можно было бы хотя бы хоть какое-то дать
There it just happens now it
Там просто бывает сейчас
was known that he was missing in action
было известно что он пропавший безвести
but at the same time they still don't say anything
но при этом всё равно ничего не говорят
even to this day they haven't sent a letter for 3
даже до сих пор письмо не отправили за 3
months Well maybe you While we're talking Look for where
месяца Ну может ты Пока говорим Поищи
he wrote what direction What
где он писал какое направление Какое
city at least so that there's some kind of connection-  that
города хотя бы чтобы привязка какая-то
was because there are a lot of
была потому что там очень много есть
such that unidentified bodies yes And in
таких что не распознанных тел да А в
Makeyevka Makeyevka yes oh there yes there
Макеевке Макеевка да о там да там
of course He was in Donetsk initially but
конечно Он в Донецке был изначально но
it seems you were sending him to Makeyevka In short
вроде бы вы направляли в Макеевку Короче
if Makeyevka most likely he
если Макеевка скорее всего ему
but  he was there something like first there
но он был там что-то там типа первые там
second and third he was the third very
вторые и третий он был третий самый
last because he was there just Well
последний потому что он там только Ну
like just arrived there in Makeyevka
типа только что прил там в Макеевку мне
these guys from the Red Cross
ребята вот эти из Красного Креста
told me there their prisoners with
рассказывали там ихние пленные э с
whom they talked they said that  in
которыми они общались то говорили что в
Makeyevka there were almost no prisoners there they were
Макеевке там пленных почти не было их
all driven like meat Yes, just to the machine guns so
всех гнали как мясо Да вот на пулемёты
that the Ukrainians would run out of
вот просто чтобы у украинцев закончились
ammunition, that is, Most likely he is lying
патроны то есть Скорее всего он лежит и
there and they can't even take his body
там даже тело его не могут забрать
because they are driving new ones they are there corpses
потому что они новые гонят они там трупы
are falling on this field Makeyevka  They've been tormenting Makeyevka for 3 years now,
на этом поле падают Макеевку 3 года уже
it's awful.
мучают это ужас
Damn it. I don't know. And what does mom say about this? What does mom say? We
Да капец Не знаю А а Что мама говорит об
try not to talk about
этом что мама стараемся не говорить об
this so that we don't cry anymore, so that we don't get
этом чтобы больше ну чтобы не плакать не
disappointed. Well, anyway, we
Разочаровываться Ну как бы всё равно уже
have to accept it somehow. Well, that's
как-то это принять надо Ну это ж
it.  -well, not a month Well, we talk about
всё-таки не не месяц Ну мы говорим об
it somehow, we think, we try to do something
этом как-то думаем стараемся что-то
Sometimes Mom asks me something, but
иногда Мама у меня что-то спрашивает но
we Nobody feels that he died, but there is no
мы Никто не чувствует что он умер но нет
such feeling that he died, but What a
такого чувства что он умер а Какое
feeling, as if  as if he were
чувство как будто бы как будто бы он
alive But somewhere even my mother says I
живой Но где-то вот даже мама говорит я
don't feel that he died I have such a
не чувствую что он умер У меня такое
feeling that he is alive anyway I
ощущение что он живой всё равно у меня
don't have the feeling that he died as if he is
нету чувства что он умер как будто бы он
alive just somewhere and that's all Well this is my mother
живой просто где-то и всё Ну это мама
herself  calms you know mom has this Well
себя успокаивает знаешь у мамы такое Ну
mom always thinks I don't know I don't want to
всегда мама считает я не знаю я не хочу
think about anything in principle just And
ни о чём думать в принципе просто А
how much And how much do they pay now for the
сколько А сколько сейчас платят за
deceased parents 4 million 4
погибшего родителям 4 млн 4
million have you heard or not I don't know how much And
млн се слышал или нет не знаю сколько А
what can be done with these 4 4 ​​million  in general, what
что можно на эти 4 4 млн вообще ка что
can you buy for 4 million an apartment in Kirov?
можно купить на 4 млн квартиру в Кирове
And how much does an apartment cost in Kirov? Well, a one-
А сколько стоит квартира в Кирове Ну
room apartment costs 4 million. So that means you can only buy a one-room apartment
однушка 4 млн Так это что только однушку
and that's it. Well, no, you can buy
можно купить и всё Ну нет можно купить
a three-room apartment, for example. But that's in a house that's already
трёшку допустим Но это в доме таком уже
very old and will be torn down
который очень старый который снесут
in a few
Через несколько
years.  it's funny how it turns out that Well, mom
лет прикольно так получается что Ну маме
was paid 4 million for this son and she
за этого сына выпла тебя 4 млн и она
will only be able to buy a
сможет только квартиру купить
one-room apartment why is it like that and
однокомнатную для чего оно так а ей эти
she needs these 4 million It would probably be better for her son to be
4 млн Ей наверное лучше бы чтобы сын был
alive Well, son Well, if the son is no longer there,
живой Да ну сына Ну если сына уже нет
she will still be paid  4 million Where would
всё равно же ей выплатят 4 млн А куда
she spend it then if not on an
она тогда дене их если не на
apartment?  Well Well what can you do now
квартиру Ну Ну что поделать сейчас
inflation prices are rising now because of
инфляция цены растут сейчас из-за
Ukraine because of this war in Russia
Украины из-за войны этой в России
problems
проблемы
started problems started because of What
начались проблемы начались из-за Какие
problems started because of Ukraine Well because of the
из-за Украины начались проблемы Ну из-за
war in principle in short Not so much because
войны в принципе короче Не то чтобы
of Ukraine What  problems what
из-за Украины Какие проблемы какие
problems inflation inflation is very strong the
проблемы инфляция инфляция очень сильно
dollar has risen because of this the ruble has fallen so
доллар поднялся из-за этого рубль упал
what Well it turns out Well
та И что Ну получается Ну вот есть у
mom has 4 million Well where can mom put these 4
мамы 4 млн Ну куда Мама может деть эти 4
million I can't understand Well most likely well they
млн Я не могу понять Ну скорее всего ну
will pay off their loan on the house and maybe  they
выплатят кредит свой на дом и возможно
will help me because as my mother
мне помогут потому что как мне мама
tells me I am the only child in the
говорит я единственный сейчас ребёнок в
family now And they will help you with something Well either studying
семье А помогут тебе чем Ну либо учёба
maybe an apartment somehow else Well that
может быть квартира как-то ещё А ну то
is, in principle it turns out Well it is logical
есть в принципе получается Ну логично
that my brother is no longer there, I can have an apartment,
что уже брата нет кварти мо ть те ляма
so it turns out yes eh  apartment It would be better
так получается да э квартира Лучше бы
if my brother was alive No, if
чтобы у меня брат был живой Не ну если
he's already gone, it doesn't matter Yes, but that's how it
его уже нет всё равно Да всё но вот так
turns out Well, what should I do now
вот получается Ну что теперь делать
Maybe it sounds right I
Может быть звучит по
don't have half a million yet to
У меня пока что нету полмиллиона чтобы
get a visa And at least
получить визу И И хотя бы
travel
попутешествовать
there Well, at least  at least something, I
там ну хотя бы что-то хоть что-то я же
can sell this apartment later  what's the
могу потом эту квартиру продать в чём
problem? Well, basically, yes, it's just better to
проблема а Ну в принципе да просто лучше
live in your own apartment than in a rented one. Well, yes, that is, it
жить своей чем съёмной Ну да то есть
turns out that your mother will buy you an apartment, like you'll
получается квартиру мама купит типа ты
already be living in it and you can
уже будешь в ней жить и можешь себе
travel, so it will be easier. Yes, you won't
путешествовать те проще будет Да ты не
spend money, of course, it's easier
будешь тратить деньги коне проще потому
because a rented one is much more expensive than
что съёмная намного дороже обходится чем
Well, usually a communal apartment in
Ну обычно коммуналку в
your own And how much is the rented communal apartment there,
своей А сколько там коммуналка съёмная
more precisely in Kirov, how much is it, well, in a one-room apartment 30
точнее в Кирове сколько ну в однушке 30
meters, the communal apartment now in winter is 4,000 no no,
мтро коммуналка сейчас зимой 4.000 нене
how much does rent
сколько аренда
cost around 20,000 20-3 Well, yes,
стоит в районе 20.000 20-3 Ну да
a one-room apartment is 200 dollars in Kirov, it
однокомнатная 200 долларов в Кирове
turns out to rent an apartment Yeah, yeah And that's how
получается снимать хату Угу Ну да А так
it works out If  like well for this when
получается Если типа ну для это когда
considering that the salary there is maximum Well
учитывая то что там зарплата максимум Ну
like sometimes it is 30-40 And the apartment is all
типа иногда бывает 30-40 А квартира все
20 Well yeah And so it turns out you already have a
20 Ну да А так получается у тебя уже
million like well they invest in at least
заче ляма типа ну инвестируют в хотя бы
a one-room apartment And you won't be
однокомнатную Да и ты уже не будешь
spending twenty on housing it turns out  well
двадцатку тратить на жильё получается ну
yeah well I don't spend my boyfriend spends
да ну я не трачу у меня парень тратит
So I don't care what your
Так что мне без разницы что что у тебя
boyfriend spends A  guy I mean
парень парень тратит А парень В смысле
spends Well I live with a guy the guy rents
тратит Ну я с парнем живу парень снимает
an apartment no And how many years have you been living together for a
квартиру не А сколько уже лет живёте
year and a half well we've been dating for three and you're
полтора года ну встречаемся три а ты с
married to him no I'm still too young to
ним расписана нет я ещё маленькая чтобы
sign no Well look Well anyway it
расписываться не Ну смотри Ну всё равно
turns out you can sign
типа получается можно расписаться Потому
Because if they take him away  svo that's how it
что если его заберут на сво так
turns out If you're not married his mom
получается Если вы не расписаны его мама
won't collect him for s he's not ready Well he
его не соберут на с он не гот Ну он
can go Like if he signs a contract there it
может пойти Типа если он там контракт
turns out his mom will get
подпишет получается так его мама получит
payments And so you are like well okay what do
выплаты А так вы так ну ладно что мне
I need money from him like damn well
мне не нужны от него деньги типа блин ну
let's sign with you suddenly if
давай мы с тобой распишемся вдруг если
you at least have money I
ты у меня хотя бы деньги будут мне это
need it why so well otherwise nothing at all no steam and
зачем так ну а так вообще ниче не пар и
no money yeah Well yeah yeah I don't even want to think
не денег да Ну да да Не хочу даже думать
about it it's all scary crap and what are you
об этом это страшно всё г а что ты
saying that you don't want to sign  and to
говоришь что расписываться не хочешь а
live Well, in what Well, you live
жить Ну а в чём Ну вы живёте разом
together Well, in principle Why not he
вместе Ну ну в принципе Почему нет он
pays even a serious relationship what what
платит важе серьёзные отношения что что
well he pays for an apartment for housing Why
ну он платит за квартиру за жильё Почему
not Well, but you don't want to sign
нет Ну так а расписываться ты не хочешь
with him That is, you  you just live
с ним То есть вы просто живёте потому
because he pays the rent No I'm with Shib
что он платит за квартиру Нет я сним Шиб
Not because he pays the rent but
Не потому что он платит за квартиру а
because Well I don't want to yet Well I don't want to
потому что Ну я ещё пока что Ну не хочу
just yet I'm 19 years old I don't want to
просто мне пока что на 19 лет Я не хочу
get married anyway - it's serious as
всё равно расписаться - это серьёзно как
if for  for me this is a serious step and I
будто бы для меня это серьёзный шаг и я
don't want to sign the marriage contract just
не хочу расписываться просто из-за того
because we live together, maybe
что мы с ним живём вместе может быть
in a year I'll find out that he's a
через год я узнаешь что он там
completely different person and then I'll
совершенно другой человек и потом такая
be like, Damn, I'll have to do all this again, all this
Блин надо будет опять это всё всё это
paperwork, this is time. Well, this is time.
оформлять документы это ну это время Ну
yes, I agree, everything here seems to be like,
да лучше согласен тут всё вроде как бы
well, this is not done, I agree,
ну это посм не делается такое согласен
yes, of course, when I am
ту да пра Конечно когда я буду уверена в
100% sure of the person, then yes, I am ready to
100% в человеке тогда да я готова
sign the marriage, but now, no, I am not
расписаться но сейчас нет я не уверена
100% sure that I want to
типа на 100% что я хочу с ним типа
sign the marriage with him  because I have
расписываться потому что я ещё за 3 года
n't fully studied it in 3 years why do I need it but
не полностью изучила мне это зачем а
well for example well I'm just
хорошо вот например ну я вот просто
wondering how do you think how best
интересно как вот ты мыслишь как лучше
to do it like this When mom buys
сделать вот э Когда мама купит 4 млн
you a one-room apartment for 4 million yes you will move to live in
однокомнатную тебе да вы переедет жить в
your own apartment so as not to pay Or you
свою квартиру чтобы не платить Или вы
Let him pay as he did And you
Пусть он типа платит как и платил А ты
will rent out yours No of course I'd rather
свою будешь сдавать Нет конечно я лучше
move into mine but he will pay for utilities
перееду в свою но за коммуналку будет
in any case because this
платить он в любом случае потому что эта
apartment was already bought with my
квартира уже куплено на деньги моих
parents' money Yeah, I get it and he thinks Well a
родителей Ага понял а он считает Ну
stranger moved in here why him
чужой человек сюда заехал почему он
should live here for free
должен бесплатно здесь
and you live for free Well these are my
жить а ты же бесплатно живёшь Ну это мои
parents not his not now you he
родители не его же не сейчас ты он
rents an apartment in which you
снимает квартиру в которой ты ти нам
give us money Well like my
родители дают деньги Ну типа мне
parents give me money I buy
родители дают деньги я покупаю на них
food there and something else an apartment
продукты там ещё что-то квартиру
for example and so on  further All the same,
например и так далее Всё равно как бы
as if 50/50, he pays for
как будто бы 50 на 50 он платит за
the apartment, I sometimes buy groceries there, I'll
квартиру я там иногда продукты куплю ещё
buy something else for the apartment, it doesn't matter whether he
что-нибудь куплю в квартиру всё равно
buys groceries or not. It just
продукты покупает или нет Да просто
turns out that he pays for the apartment now,
получается Он платит сейчас за квартиру
and you and he buy groceries, yes  And
а продукты вы и ты и он покупаешь да А
if and if you move into your apartment
если а если вы переедет в твою квартиру
yes then you won't pay for the apartment
да то ты не будешь платить за квартиру
but he has to pay for utilities
но он должен платить за коммуналку
because he is a stranger I wonder well
потому что он чужой человек интересно ну
utilities are 4,000 4,000 a month is that
коммуналка 4.000 4.000 в месяц это что
a lot or what No well you You  you just say
много что ли Не ну ты Ты просто говоришь
he's a miracle man that he should
он чудо человек что он должен бесплатно
live there for free No well and the butt also no well it's
там жить Не ну а попа тоже не ну
practical you're not with you you have an
практично ты не у тебя вот у тебя
American grip we Americans too
американская хватка мы американцы тоже
we all count yes like you live pay like you
мы всё считаем да типа живёшь плати типа
know or supports pay everything is super Yes
знаешь или содержит плати всё супер Да
everything is clear here here  right well interesting
тут всё чётко тут правильно ну интересно
yes and uh there is another option The thing is
да а ээ есть ещё такой вариант Дело в
that if he lives in your
том что если он будет жить в твоей
apartment yes uh he you if you
квартире да ээ он ты если бы её сдавала
rented it out you would get 20,000 rubles a
в аренду ты бы получала 20.000 руб в
month
месяц
so since since the owner well well there are
так поскольку раз же хозя ну ну бывают
tenants they can me  to tear apart the apartment I
жильцы они могут мне квартиру разнести Я
then for repairs no I don't mean yes then
потом на ремонт не не имею в виду да то
look it turns out we can consider
смотри получается можно рассматривать
So you live in your apartment Yes in
Так что ты живёшь в своей квартире Да в
part of the apartment And he as a cohabitant as
части квартиры А он как сожитель как
rents half of the apartment for 10,000 That
арендует половину квартиры за 10.000 То
is he can pay you another 10,000
есть он тебе может ещё 10.000
he sent me like that  he'll say yes,
оплачивать он меня пошли такой скажет да
go, I'll leave, it's better and I'll live for free,
пошла я уеду лучше и буду бесплатно
grandma, well, wait. That is, you
жить бабушки ну подожди То есть ты
provide housing, and he has to live in Bratovo
предоставляемую а он должен в братово
for free. Let him pay
жилье бесплатно жить Пусть он оплачивает
for depreciation, for
на амортизацию на
repairs. Well, well.  somehow if a guy proposed to me like that
ремонт Ну ну как-то если бы мне бы так
I would say well that's
парень предложил Я бы сказала ну это
creepy
стрёмно
why Well I don't know Well it's like
почему Ну не знаю Ну это как будто бы
somehow well I don't know no way Well look
как-то ну не знаю не побо Ну смотри если
if if you Imagine that you rent
бы если бы вы Представь что вы снимаете
an apartment from your parents yes Yes  you
квартиру у своих родителей да Да ты
pay 10,000 and he pays 10,000 but
платишь 10.000 и он 10.000 но родители
your parents just give you back 10,000 because
тебе просто 10.000 возвращают Потому что
you're their daughter and they don't give it back to him
ты ихняя дочка А ему не возвращают
because he's a weirdo. Well, it's logical if
потому что он левый тип Ну логично если
he lives in someone else's apartment why
он живёт в чужой квартире почему он
should he live for free. Well, when a girl
должен жить бесплатно Ну а когда девушка
moves into a guy's apartment She doesn't
заезжает в квартиру парня Она же не
pays him 10,000 Well, that's right Because
платит ему 10.000 Ну Правильно Потому
And what should you pay him Well,
что А что ты должна ему платить Ну
because you're a girl Well, that's right Yes, let him
потому что ты девушка Ну правильно Да он
Well, damn, that's
пусть Ну блин
it Me too Look, I'm here in California,
всё Я тоже Смотри я тут в Калифорнии
like, I was dating this Mexican woman,
типа я встречался с одной мексиканкой
like, a girl Yes, her parents,
типа ну девочкой Да у неё типа родители
like, had a room  yes they rented it to us and I
типа имели комнату да нам сдали и я
paid for the room we lived with her parents
платил за комнату мы жили у её родителей
in the house
в доме
in her room it turns out yes I pay extra
в её комнате получается да я доплачивать
for part of the room it's normal practice
за часть комнаты это нормальная практика
because A man because  what is
потому что А мужчина потому что
right Well and he I say that is well
правильно Ну и он я говорю то есть ну
why should he be free Let him
почему он должен бесплат Пусть
spin Well that is right he can't
крутится Ну это правильно не может на
earn for his own this is how it is premises yes
своё заработать это как оно помещение да
then let him pay in short for your brother
то пусть платит короче за твой брат
earned for you what should he
заработал для тебя что он должен
use for free Your brother died and
бесплатно пользоваться Твой брат умер а
he will be  just [ __ ] sit on the couch
он будет просто блин на диване сидеть
watching
смотреть
football too yeah So
футбол тоже да Так что
here how are they
тут как они
just brother Yes one-room apartment well in short Yes
просто брата Да однушка ну короче Да
brother Let's live one-room apartment Dan
брат Давай однушку Дан жить
how they are just mercantile they don't care
какие они просто меркантильные им
about brother don't care don't care about
плевать на брата плевать на плевать на
man it's just
мужика просто
brutal it was bomb Simo that's the whole
жесть это было бомби Симо вот вся
essence of Russia Let's  like squeak
сущность России Давайте лайк писка
comment more of
комент побольше
them subscribe to y Telegram right now
их подпишись на й Telegram прям зараз
axis win and
ось вин а
popk this is very and very important busy us
попк це дуже и дуже важливо заня нас
through srr in ny ban and very many videos I do
через срр в ньй бан и дуже багато вдео
not show to people at times I do not show
не показу людям вчасно не показуе
information about streams That is why in order for
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
us Mali operational links are written
ми Мали оперативний звязок пишиться
directly  now and while there in telegram okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video still tsikava  and useful information
видео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we will pon you sing operational links
и мы пон вама пой оперативный звязок
in the future and show you about this
залежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine subscribe
YouTube Слава Украине подпишись